[{"id": 0, "question": "1. What is the goal of Layer 3 switching?\n", "correct_answer": ["to process packets at Layer 2 switching speeds while utilizing the scalability of routing\n"], "answers": ["to process packets at Layer 2 switching speeds while utilizing the scalability of routing\n", "to provide a better path to the Internet without using routing protocols\n", "to implement the routing process by using routed protocols\n", "to integrate all of the networking functions into one device\n"]}, {"id": 1, "question": "2. Which two statements are true about routed ports on a multilayer switch? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["To create a routed port requires removal of Layer 2 port functionality with the no switchport interface configuration command.\n", "A routed port is not associated with a particular VLAN.\n"], "answers": ["To create a routed port requires removal of Layer 2 port functionality with the no switchport interface configuration command.\n", "A routed port is a physical switch port with Layer 2 capability.\n", "A routed port is not associated with a particular VLAN.\n", "A routed port behaves like a regular router interface and supports VLAN subinterfaces.\n", "The interface vlan global configuration command is used to create a routed port.\n"]}, {"id": 2, "question": "3. Which two statements are true about the 802.1Q trunking protocol? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["The native VLAN interface configurations must match at both ends of the link or frames could be dropped.\n", "Untagged frames will be placed in the configured native VLAN of a port.\n"], "answers": ["The native VLAN interface configurations must match at both ends of the link or frames could be dropped.\n", "Untagged frames will be placed in the configured native VLAN of a port.\n", "Private VLAN configurations are not supported.\n", "It is a proprietary protocol that is supported on Cisco switches only.\n"]}, {"id": 3, "question": "4. Which technology does CEF switching use on Cisco hardware-based routers to forward packets?\n", "correct_answer": ["forwarding engines implemented in specialized ASICs\n"], "answers": ["router general-purpose CPU\n", "interVLAN routing using subinterfaces\n", "forwarding engines implemented in specialized ASICs\n", "route processors using stateful switchover\n"]}, {"id": 4, "question": "5. What type of specialized memory is used to facilitate high performance switching in Cisco multilayer switches?\n", "correct_answer": ["ternary content addressable memory (TCAM)\n"], "answers": ["address resolution protocol (ARP) memory\n", "ternary content addressable memory (TCAM)\n", "Cisco Express Forwarding (CEF) memory\n", "content-addressable memory (CAM)\n"]}, {"id": 5, "question": "6. Which protocol is required for Cisco Express Forwarding to be able to successfully forward packets on a multilayer switch?\n", "correct_answer": ["Address Resolution Protocol\n"], "answers": ["VLAN Trunking Protocol\n", "Cisco Discovery Protocol\n", "Spanning Tree Protocol\n", "Address Resolution Protocol\n", "Dynamic Trunking Protocol\n"]}, {"id": 6, "question": "7. Which two network design features require Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) to ensure correct network operation? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["removing single points of failure with multiple Layer 2 switches\n", "redundant links between Layer 2 switches\n"], "answers": ["link-state dynamic routing that provides redundant routes\n", "removing single points of failure with multiple Layer 2 switches\n", "implementing VLANs to contain broadcasts\n", "static default routes\n", "redundant links between Layer 2 switches\n"]}, {"id": 7, "question": "8. If left to default configuration settings, what will determine which switch becomes the spanning-tree root bridge in a Layer 2 domain?\n", "correct_answer": ["the lowest switch MAC address\n"], "answers": ["the highest bridge priority\n", "the lowest switch MAC address\n", "the highest bridge ID\n", "the highest management IP address\n"]}, {"id": 8, "question": "9. During the implementation of Spanning Tree Protocol, all switches are rebooted by the network administrator. What is the first step of the spanning-tree election process?\n", "correct_answer": ["All the switches send out BPDUs advertising themselves as the root bridge.\n"], "answers": ["Each switch determines the best path to forward traffic.\n", "All the switches send out BPDUs advertising themselves as the root bridge.\n", "Each switch determines what port to block to prevent a loop from occurring.\n", "Each switch with a lower root ID than its neighbor will not send BPDUs.\n"]}, {"id": 9, "question": "10. After the election of the root bridge has been completed, how will switches find the best paths to the root bridge?\n", "correct_answer": ["Each switch will analyze the sum of all port costs to reach the root and use the path with the lowest cost.\n"], "answers": ["Each switch will analyze the sum of the hops to reach the root and use the path with the fewest hops.\n", "Each switch will analyze the port states of all neighbors and use the designated ports to forward traffic to the root.\n", "Each switch will analyze the BID of all neighbors to reach the root and use the path through the lowest BID neighbors.\n", "Each switch will analyze the sum of all port costs to reach the root and use the path with the lowest cost.\n"]}, {"id": 10, "question": "11. Which statement describes the term bridge priority in the operation of STP?\n", "correct_answer": ["It is a value that decides which switch can become the root bridge.\n"], "answers": ["It is a value that decides which switch can become the root bridge.\n", "It is a value that is used, in the event of a loop, to decide which port on the switch must be put into forwarding state.\n", "It is a feature that allows access ports to bypass the earlier learning and listening states and forward traffic immediately.\n", "It is a safety mechanism that shuts down ports configured with STP portfast upon receipt of a BPDU.\n"]}, {"id": 11, "question": "12. Which three components are combined to form a bridge ID?\n", "correct_answer": ["MAC address\n", "bridge priority\n", "extended system ID\n"], "answers": ["MAC address\n", "cost\n", "bridge priority\n", "IP address\n", "port ID\n", "extended system ID\n"]}, {"id": 12, "question": "13. In which two port states does a switch learn MAC addresses and process BPDUs in a PVST network? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["learning\n", "forwarding\n"], "answers": ["listening\n", "disabled\n", "learning\n", "forwarding\n", "blocking\n"]}, {"id": 13, "question": "14. Which STP priority configuration would ensure that a switch would always be the root switch?\n", "correct_answer": ["spanning-tree vlan 10 priority 0\n"], "answers": ["spanning-tree vlan 10 priority 0\n", "spanning-tree vlan 10 priority 61440\n", "spanning-tree vlan 10 priority 4096\n", "spanning-tree vlan 10 root primary\n"]}, {"id": 14, "question": "15. Refer to the exhibit. The network has converged and Switch_6 has been elected root bridge of the STP tree. However, network traffic analysis indicates that Switch_1 would be a better root bridge. How can the network administrator make this change, assuming that the spanning-tree priorities are at the default settings?\n", "correct_answer": ["Set the bridge priority of Switch_1 to 4,096.\n"], "answers": ["Set the bridge priority of Switch_1 to 4,096.\n", "Set the bridge priority of Switch_6 to 255.\n", "Set the bridge priority of Switch_6 to 65,565.\n", "Set the bridge priority of Switch_1 to 32,768.\n"]}, {"id": 15, "question": "16. Why is it important that the network administrator consider the spanning-tree network diameter when choosing the root bridge?\n", "correct_answer": ["BPDUs may be discarded because of expiring timers.\n"], "answers": ["BPDUs may be discarded because of expiring timers.\n", "The network diameter limitation is 9.\n", "The cabling distance between the switches is 100 meters.\n", "Convergence is slower as the BPDU travels away from the root.\n"]}, {"id": 16, "question": "17. A network administrator enters the spanning-tree portfast bpduguard default command. What is the result of this command being issued on a Cisco switch?\n", "correct_answer": ["Any switch port that has been configured with PortFast will be error-disabled if it receives a BPDU.\n"], "answers": ["Any switch port that receives a BPDU will ignore the BPDU message.\n", "Any switch port will be error-disabled if it receives a BPDU.\n", "Any trunk ports will be allowed to connect to the network immediately, rather than waiting to converge.\n", "Any switch port that has been configured with PortFast will be error-disabled if it receives a BPDU.\n"]}, {"id": 17, "question": "18. In what situation would a network administrator most likely implement root guard?\n", "correct_answer": ["on all switch ports that connect to another switch that is not the root bridge\n"], "answers": ["on all switch ports that connect to a Layer 3 device\n", "on all switch ports that connect to another switch\n", "on all switch ports that connect to host devices\n", "on all switch ports (used or unused)\n", "on all switch ports that connect to another switch that is not the root bridge\n"]}, {"id": 18, "question": "19. Which two statements describe the MST internal spanning tree instance? (Choose two)\n", "correct_answer": ["It is always instance 0.\n", "It runs on all switch port interfaces of switches in the MST region.\n"], "answers": ["It carries all VLANs traffic.\n", "It carries identical setup information among interconnected MST regions.\n", "It is always instance 0.\n", "It runs on all switch port interfaces of switches that are designated as root bridges.\n", "It runs on all switch port interfaces of switches in the MST region.\n"]}, {"id": 19, "question": "20. What are the two options that describe the effects of the spanning-tree portfast command? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["If a switch port is configured with PortFast, it is an access port that immediately transitions from a blocking to forwarding state.\n", "Portfast enables the port to bypass the listening and learning states of STP.\n"], "answers": ["Portfast bypasses the learning state and moves immediately into blocking.\n", "If a switch port is configured with PortFast, it is an access port that immediately transitions from a blocking to forwarding state.\n", "Portfast enables the port to bypass the listening and learning states of STP.\n", "Enabling PortFast on trunks that connect to other switches improves convergence.\n", "If the switch port is configured with PortFast, it waits 15 seconds before transitioning from a blocking to forwarding state.\n"]}, {"id": 20, "question": "21. Which LACP technology is used for designating a specific number of member interfaces that must remain active in order for the EtherChannel bundle to be usable?\n", "correct_answer": ["LACP min-links\n"], "answers": ["LACP port priority\n", "LACP fast\n", "LACP min-links\n", "LACP system priority\n"]}, {"id": 21, "question": "22. Which statement describes the term root port in the operation of STP?\n", "correct_answer": ["It is a port that connects to the root bridge or an upstream switch in the spanning-tree topology.\n"], "answers": ["It indicates that the port has transitioned from a blocking state and can send or receive BPDUs, but cannot forward any other network traffic.\n", "It is a port state that can forward all network traffic and can update the MAC address table.\n", "It is a port state that can modify the MAC address table with any network traffic that it receives, but only forwards BPDUs and not any other network traffic.\n", "It is a port that connects to the root bridge or an upstream switch in the spanning-tree topology.\n"]}, {"id": 22, "question": "23. What are two configuration parameters that must match for all switches in the same MST region? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["region name\n", "version number\n"], "answers": ["bridge priority\n", "region name\n", "version number\n", "trunk link encapsulation method\n", "port status\n"]}, {"id": 23, "question": "24. Assuming that all switches in a network have the default bridge priority for each MST instance, what effect does the command spanning-tree mst 10 root seconday have when entered on a single switch?\n", "correct_answer": ["sets the bridge priority on the switch to 28672 for MST instance 10\n"], "answers": ["sets the bridge priority on the switch to 28672 for MST instance 10\n", "sets the bridge priority on the switch to 24586 for MST instance 10\n", "sets the bridge priority on the switch to 24582 for MST instance 10\n", "sets the bridge priority on the switch to 24576 for MST instance 10\n"]}, {"id": 24, "question": "25. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator issues the show spanning-tree command to verify the MST configuration. Which two conclusions can be drawn based on the output? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["SW1 is the root bridge for instance 1.\n", "SW1 is running IEEE 802.1S protocol.\n"], "answers": ["SW1 is running IEEE 802.1W STP protocol.\n", "SW1 is the root bridge for instance 1.\n", "The command spanning-tree mst 1 root secondary was entered.\n", "SW1 is running IEEE 802.1S protocol.\n", "PortFast is enabled on ports Gi1/0/2 and Gi1/0/3.\n"]}, {"id": 25, "question": "26. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring MST tuning on SW1. The objective is to change the path cost value of the interface Gi1/0/1 to represent a higher-speed bandwidth link. Which value could be used in the command spanning-tree mst 0 cost for this task?\n", "correct_answer": ["1\n"], "answers": ["0\n", "1\n", "24576\n", "32768\n"]}, {"id": 26, "question": "27. What are two misconfigurations within an MST region that might introduce port blocking unintentionally? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["trunk link pruning\n", "VLAN assignment to the IST\n"], "answers": ["trunk link pruning\n", "too many VLANs assigned to an instance\n", "VLAN assignment to the IST\n", "misconfigured revision number across the MST region\n", "misconfigured region name across the MST region\n"]}, {"id": 27, "question": "28. How does an MST region send VLAN information through the PVST simulation mechanism to a switch that runs PVST+?\n", "correct_answer": ["It sends out PVST+ BPDUs, one for each VLAN, using the information from the IST.\n"], "answers": ["It sends out PVST+ BPDUs, one for each VLAN, using the information from the IST.\n", "It sends out one PVST+ BPDU with the information from the IST.\n", "It sends out one PVST+ BPDU that maps all VLANs into VLAN1.\n", "It sends out multiple PVST+ BPDUs, one for each VLAN, plus the IST.\n"]}, {"id": 28, "question": "29. Which two VTP modes allow for the creation, modification, and deletion of VLANs on the local switch? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["transparent\n", "server\n"], "answers": ["transparent\n", "distribution\n", "client\n", "server\n", "slave\n", "master\n"]}, {"id": 29, "question": "30. Given the following configuration, which two statements are true? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["This switch can send and receive advertisements from only the Cisco domain.\n", "This switch can create, modify, and delete all VLANs within the Cisco domain.\n"], "answers": ["This switch can advertise its VLAN configuration to other switches in the Cisco domain only, but can receive advertisements from other domains.\n", "The password will prevent unauthorized routers from participating in the Cisco domain.\n", "This switch can send and receive advertisements from only the Cisco domain.\n", "This switch can create, modify, and delete all VLANs within the Cisco domain.\n", "This switch maintains a full list of all VLANs and can create VLANs, but cannot delete or modify existing VLANs.\n"]}, {"id": 30, "question": "31. Which Cisco proprietary protocol is used for dynamically forming a trunk connection between two switches?\n", "correct_answer": ["DTP\n"], "answers": ["VTP\n", "STP\n", "DTP\n", "PAgP\n"]}, {"id": 31, "question": "32. Which is a characteristic of EtherChannel?\n", "correct_answer": ["STP treats all interfaces in an EtherChannel bundle as a single logical link.\n"], "answers": ["STP treats all interfaces in an EtherChannel bundle as a single logical link.\n", "EtherChannel uses physical ports that have been upgraded to provide a faster connection.\n", "EtherChannel configuration is applied to each physical port.\n", "STP will not block redundant EtherChannel bundles between two switches.\n"]}, {"id": 32, "question": "33. Refer to the exhibit. The administrator tried to create an EtherChannel between S1 and the other two switches via the commands that are shown, but was unsuccessful. What is the problem?\n", "correct_answer": ["Traffic cannot be sent to two different switches through the same EtherChannel link.\n"], "answers": ["Traffic can only be sent to two different switches if EtherChannel is implemented on Gigabit Ethernet interfaces.\n", "Traffic can only be sent to two different switches if EtherChannel is implemented on Layer 3 switches.\n", "Traffic cannot be sent to two different switches, but only to two different devices like an EtherChannel-enabled server and a switch.\n", "Traffic cannot be sent to two different switches through the same EtherChannel link.\n"]}, {"id": 33, "question": "34. Refer to the exhibit. An EtherChannel was configured between switches S1 and S2, but the interfaces do not form an EtherChannel. What is the problem?\n", "correct_answer": ["The EtherChannel was not configured with the same allowed range of VLANs on each interface.\n"], "answers": ["The EtherChannel was not configured with the same allowed range of VLANs on each interface.\n", "The switch ports were not configured with speed and duplex mode.\n", "The switch ports have to be configured as access ports with each port having a VLAN assigned.\n", "The interface port-channel number has to be different on each switch.\n"]}, {"id": 34, "question": "35. Which two DTP mode combinations will form a trunk link between two switches? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["trunk and dynamic desirable\n", "dynamic auto and dynamic desirable\n"], "answers": ["access and dynamic auto\n", "dynamic auto and dynamic auto\n", "trunk and access\n", "trunk and dynamic desirable\n", "dynamic auto and dynamic desirable\n"]}, {"id": 35, "question": "36. Which statement is true about the port roles of the 802.1w Rapid Spanning Tree Protocol?\n", "correct_answer": ["An alternate or backup port can immediately change to a forwarding state without waiting for the network to converge.\n"], "answers": ["Cisco-proprietary enhancements to the legacy 802.1D, such as UplinkFast and BackboneFast, are compatible with RSTP.\n", "An alternate or backup port can immediately change to a forwarding state without waiting for the network to converge.\n", "It takes an edge port 15 seconds to go from blocking to forwarding.\n", "Ports are manually configured to be in the designated role.\n"]}, {"id": 36, "question": "37. Which technology is used to protect the switched infrastructure from problems caused by receiving BPDUs on ports that should not be receiving them?\n", "correct_answer": ["BPDU guard\n"], "answers": ["Loop guard\n", "PortFast\n", "BPDU guard\n", "RSPAN\n", "Root guard\n"]}, {"id": 37, "question": "38. Which statement describes the term blocking in the operation of STP?\n", "correct_answer": ["It is a port state that is enabled but does not forward any traffic to ensure that a loop does not occur.\n"], "answers": ["It is a port state that can modify the MAC address table with any network traffic that it receives, but only forwards BPDUs and not any other network traffic.\n", "It indicates that the port is in an administratively off position.\n", "It is a port state that is enabled but does not forward any traffic to ensure that a loop does not occur.\n", "It indicates that the port has transitioned from a blocking state and can send or receive BPDUs, but cannot forward any other network traffic.\n"]}, {"id": 38, "question": "39. The network administrator wants to configure a switch to pass VLAN update information to other switches in the domain but not update its own local VLAN database. Which two steps should the administrator perform to achieve this? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["Configure the switch with the same VTP domain name as other switches in the network.\n", "Configure the VTP mode of the switch to transparent.\n"], "answers": ["Configure VTP version 1 on the switch.\n", "Configure the switch with the same VTP domain name as other switches in the network.\n", "Verify that the switch has a higher configuration revision number.\n", "Reset the VTP counters.\n", "Configure the VTP mode of the switch to transparent.\n"]}, {"id": 39, "question": "40. Which LACP technology is used for designating whuch member interfaces will be active in a port-channel configuration where there are more member interfaces than the maximum allowed?\n", "correct_answer": ["LACP port priority\n"], "answers": ["LACP min-links\n", "LACP port priority\n", "LACP system priority\n", "LACP fast\n"]}, {"id": 40, "question": "41. Which LACP technology can identify and remove a LACP enabled link from an EtherChannel within three seconds when the link is experiencing connectivity issues?\n", "correct_answer": ["LACP fast\n"], "answers": ["LACP min-links\n", "LACP port priority\n", "LACP system priority\n", "LACP fast\n"]}, {"id": 41, "question": "42. Which two statements descibe the MST internal spanning tree instance? (Choose two)\n", "correct_answer": ["It is always instance 0.\n", "It runs on all switch port interfaces of the switches in the MST region.\n"], "answers": ["It runs on all switch port interfaces of switches that are designated as root bridges.\n", "It is always instance 0.\n", "It carries identical setup information among interconnected MST regions.\n", "It runs on all switch port interfaces of the switches in the MST region.\n", "It carries all VLANs traffic.\n"]}, {"id": 42, "question": "43. Which statement describes the term root bridge in the operation of STP?\n", "correct_answer": ["It is a switch that is at the top of the spanning tree and whose ports are all forwarding and are all categorized as designated ports.\n"], "answers": ["It is a switch that is at the top of the spanning tree and whose ports are all forwarding and are all categorized as designated ports.\n", "It is a value that decides which switch can become the root bridge.\n", "It is a feature that prevents any alternative or root ports from becoming designated ports because of a loss of BPDUs on the root port.\n", "It is a safety mechanism that shuts down ports configured with STP portfast upon receipt of a BPDU.\n"]}, {"id": 43, "question": "44. Refer to the exhibit. Access1 is a new switch that is to be connected as a VTP client to the network once it has been configured. Given the output generated by the VTP server switch Dist-2, which series of configuration commands would successfully introduce the client switch into the VTP domain?\n", "correct_answer": ["Access1(config)# vtp mode client\n", "Access1(config)# vtp domain MYCORP\n", "Access1(config)# vtp version 2\n", "Access1(config)# vtp password ITrustYou\n"], "answers": ["Access1(config)# vtp mode client\n", "Access1(config)# vtp domain MYCORP\n", "Access1(config)# vtp version 2\n", "Access1(config)# vtp password ITrustYou\n", "//\n", "Access1(config)# vtp mode client\n", "Access1(config)# vtp domain mycorp\n", "Access1(config)# vtp password ITrustYou\n", "Access1(config)# vtp mode client\n", "//\n", "Access1(config)# vtp domain mycorp\n", "Access1(config)# vtp password ITrustYou\n", "Access1(config)# vtp mode client\n", "//\n", "Access1(config)# vtp domain Mycorp\n", "Access1(config)# vtp version 2\n", "Access1(config)# vtp password ITrustYou\n"]}, {"id": 44, "question": "45. Which LACP technology is used for designating which member interfaces will be active in a port-channel configuration where there are more member interfaces than the maximum allowed?\n", "correct_answer": ["LACP port priority\n"], "answers": ["LACP min-links\n", "LACP system priority\n", "LACP port priority\n", "LACP fast\n"]}, {"id": 45, "question": "46. Which statement describes the term root guard in the operation of STP?\n", "correct_answer": ["It is a feature that prevents a configured port from becoming a root port.\n"], "answers": ["It is a feature that prevents any alternative or root ports from becoming designated ports because of a loss of BPDUs on the root port.\n", "It is a feature that prevents a configured port from becoming a root port.\n", "It is a value that decides which switch can become the root bridge.\n", "It is a safety mechanism that shuts down ports configured with STP portfast upon receipt of a BPDU.\n"]}, {"id": 46, "question": "47. Which statement describes the term forwarding in the operation of STP?\n", "correct_answer": ["It is a port state that can forward all network traffic and can update the MAC address table.\n"], "answers": ["It is a port state that can modify the MAC address table with any network traffic that it receives, but only forwards BPDUs and not any other network traffic.\n", "It is a port state that can forward all network traffic and can update the MAC address table.\n", "It is a port state that is enabled but does not forward any traffic to ensure that a loop does not occur.\n", "It indicates that the port has transitioned from a blocking state and can send or receive BPDUs, but cannot forward any other network traffic.\n"]}, {"id": 47, "question": "1. What TCP port is used by BGP to exchange messages between routers?\n", "correct_answer": ["179\n"], "answers": ["443\n", "58\n", "179\n", "22\n"]}, {"id": 48, "question": "2. Refer to the exhibit. Autonomous system 65500 is routing traffic between two external BGP autonomous systems, autonomous system 65200 and autonomous system 65100. Synchronization is disabled on BGP in autonomous system 65500. Which routers should have IBGP peer relationships for routing between autonomous system 65200 and autonomous system 65100 to work properly?\n", "correct_answer": ["R1, R3, R4, and R5\n"], "answers": ["ISPA, R1, R5, and ISPB\n", "R1, R3, and R4\n", "R1 and R5\n", "R1, R3, R4, and R5\n"]}, {"id": 49, "question": "3. What type of BGP message precedes the successful formation of a BGP peering session?\n", "correct_answer": ["open\n"], "answers": ["keepalive\n", "established\n", "withdraw\n", "open\n", "update\n"]}, {"id": 50, "question": "4. Question as presented: Match the values to AFI and SAFI extensions supported by MBGP. (Not all options are used.)\n", "correct_answer": ["IPv4\n", "IPv6\n", "unicast\n", "multicast\n"], "answers": ["IPv4\n", "IPv6\n", "unicast\n", "multicast\n"]}, {"id": 51, "question": "5. What is the order in determining the BGP router ID?\n", "correct_answer": ["statically defined, the highest IP address of any active loopback interfaces, and the highest IP address of any active interfaces\n"], "answers": ["statically defined, the highest IP address of any active interfaces, and the highest IP address of any active loopback interfaces\n", "statically defined, the highest IP address of any active loopback interfaces, and the highest IP address of any active interfaces\n", "the highest IP address of any active interfaces, statically defined, and the highest IP address of any active loopback interfaces\n", "the highest IP address of any active loopback interfaces, statically defined, and the highest IP address of any active interfaces\n"]}, {"id": 52, "question": "6. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring BGP on a router. Which configuration step is needed in order to establish the BGP session with the neighbor router?\n", "correct_answer": ["Initialize and activate the address family.\n"], "answers": ["Configure the keepalive timer.\n", "Initialize and activate the address family.\n", "Advertise the networks attached to the router.\n", "Restart the BGP process.\n"]}, {"id": 53, "question": "7. Refer to the exhibit. Which two configurations will allow router R1 to establish a neighbor relationship with router R2? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["R1(config)# router bgp 65001\n", "R1(config-router)# network 192.168.10.0\n", "R1(config-router)# neighbor 209.165.200.226 remote-as 65002\n", "//\n", "R2(config)# router bgp 65002\n", "R2(config-router)# network 192.168.20.0\n", "R2(config-router)# neighbor 209.165.200.225 remote-as 65001\n"], "answers": ["R1(config)# router bgp 65002\n", "R1(config-router)# network 192.168.20.0\n", "R1(config-router)# neighbor 209.165.200.225 remote-as 65001\n", "//\n", "R2(config)# router bgp 65002\n", "R2(config-router)# network 192.168.10.0\n", "//\n", "R1(config)# router bgp 65001\n", "R1(config-router)# network 192.168.20.0\n", "//\n", "R1(config)# router bgp 65001\n", "R1(config-router)# network 192.168.10.0\n", "R1(config-router)# neighbor 209.165.200.226 remote-as 65002\n", "//\n", "R2(config)# router bgp 65002\n", "R2(config-router)# network 192.168.20.0\n", "R2(config-router)# neighbor 209.165.200.225 remote-as 65001\n", "//\n", "R2(config)# router bgp 65002\n", "R2(config-router)# network 192.168.10.0\n", "R2(config-router)# neighbor 209.165.200.226 remote-as 65002\n"]}, {"id": 54, "question": "8. Which BGP routers will become peers and share routing information?\n", "correct_answer": ["BGP routers that are configured with the neighbor command\n"], "answers": ["BGP routers that are configured with the same network command\n", "BGP routers that are configured with the same peer command\n", "BGP routers that are configured with the neighbor command\n", "BGP routers that share routing information with all routers in the same AS by default\n"]}, {"id": 55, "question": "9. Which two statements describe the configuration differences when MP-BGP is applied using the IPv6 protocol compared to IPv4 protocol? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["The IPv6 address family must be initialized and the neighbor activated.\n", "Routers with only IPv6 addressing must have the BGP RID statically defined.\n"], "answers": ["The IPv6 address family must be initialized and the neighbor activated.\n", "Routers with only IPv6 addressing must have the BGP RID statically defined.\n", "IPv4 addresses cannot be used to define a BGP RID.\n", "IPv6 uses multicast to establish neighbor sessions.\n", "Routers with only IPv6 addressing must use AS numbers beyond 65535.\n"]}, {"id": 56, "question": "10. A network administrator is configuring IPv6 route summarization on a BGP router. The objective is to aggregate the IPv6 networks from 2001:db8:0:0::/64 to 2001:db8:0:35::/64 into a single summary route. Which aggregation command should be used for the task?\n", "correct_answer": ["aggregate-address 2001:db8::/58 summary-only\n"], "answers": ["aggregate-address 2001:db8::/60 summary-only\n", "aggregate-address 2001:db8::/61 summary-only\n", "aggregate-address 2001:db8::/58 summary-only\n", "aggregate-address 2001:db8::/59 summary-only\n"]}, {"id": 57, "question": "11. Refer to the exhibit. What is used to exchange routing information between routers within each AS?\n", "correct_answer": ["IGP routing protocols\n"], "answers": ["default routing\n", "IGP routing protocols\n", "EGP routing protocols\n", "static routing\n"]}, {"id": 58, "question": "12. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring BGP on a router. What network layer protocol and function are enabled for the BGP session?\n", "correct_answer": ["IPv4 protocol with unicast communication.\n"], "answers": ["IPv4 protocol with TCP connections.\n", "IPv4 protocol with all the functions.\n", "IPv4 protocol with unicast communication.\n", "IPv4 protocol with both unicast and multicast communications.\n"]}, {"id": 59, "question": "13. Which BGP state is the one where BGP initiates the TCP connection and sends an Open message to the sender?\n", "correct_answer": ["Connect\n"], "answers": ["Passive\n", "Connect\n", "OpenSent\n", "Established\n"]}, {"id": 60, "question": "14. Which BGP attribute includes a complete list of all the ASNs that the prefix advertisement has traversed from its source AS?\n", "correct_answer": ["AS_Path\n"], "answers": ["Local Preference (LocPrf)\n", "Multiple-exit discriminator (MED)\n", "Weight\n", "AS_Path\n"]}, {"id": 61, "question": "15. Refer to the exhibit. For which autonomous system would running BGP not be appropriate?\n", "correct_answer": ["65003\n"], "answers": ["65004\n", "65005\n", "65003\n", "65002\n"]}, {"id": 62, "question": "16. A company is deploying BGP multihoming to provide internet connection redundancy. Which method can be used to avoid the internet transit routing situation?\n", "correct_answer": ["applying outbound BGP route policies that only allow for local BGP routes to be advertised\n"], "answers": ["deploying iBGP routing in all routers within the local AS\n", "ensuring that no IGP session is running on the local BGP routers\n", "designating a data center or a specific location to handle the internet transit traffic\n", "applying outbound BGP route policies that only allow for local BGP routes to be advertised\n"]}, {"id": 63, "question": "17. Refer to the exhibit. Which statement describes the condition when the BGP route-map TEST permit 40 command is processed and what is the result of processing?\n", "correct_answer": ["All incoming networks that do not match ACL1, ACL2, and ACL3 will match and be allowed.\n"], "answers": ["Only networks that do not match ACL3 will match and be allowed.\n", "Incoming networks that match ACL1, ACL2, and ACL3 will match and be allowed.\n", "All incoming networks that do not match ACL1, ACL2, and ACL3 will match, but will be dropped because no action is specified.\n", "All incoming networks that do not match ACL1, ACL2, and ACL3 will match and be allowed.\n"]}, {"id": 64, "question": "18. A company is deploying BGP multihoming to provide network connection redundancy for several branch locations. One of the network design objectives is to provide deterministic routing among company locations during failover by providing a specific location to handle branch transit traffic. Which two design criteria should be applied to the specific facility? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["The bandwidth can be sized according to the traffic needs.\n", "The routing pattern is bidirectional and predictable.\n"], "answers": ["The bandwidth can be sized according to the traffic needs.\n", "The facility should be in a central place from all company locations.\n", "OSPF is the preferred IGP for the facility.\n", "The routing pattern is bidirectional and predictable.\n", "BGP route policies should apply to only allow for local BGP routes to be advertised.\n"]}, {"id": 65, "question": "19. A network administrator is configuring a prefix list with the ip prefix-list command. What is the best practice in dealing with the sequence number in creating a prefix list?\n", "correct_answer": ["Sequence numbers should leave enough space to accommodate additional entries.\n"], "answers": ["Sequence numbers should leave enough space to accommodate additional entries.\n", "Sequence numbers should start with 1.\n", "Sequence numbers should be no higher than 100.\n", "Sequence numbers should be incremented by 2.\n"]}, {"id": 66, "question": "20. A network administrator is configuring a prefix list with the command\n", "correct_answer": ["2001:db8:abcd:34::/62\n", "2001:db8:abcd:36::/63\n"], "answers": ["2001:db8:abcd:30::/60\n", "2001:db8:abcd:34::/62\n", "2001:db8:abcd:20::/62\n", "2001:db8:abcd:36::/63\n", "2001:db8:abcd:60::/64\n"]}, {"id": 67, "question": "21. Question as presented: Match the route map component to the description. (Not all options are used.)\n", "correct_answer": ["None\n", "None\n", "None\n", "None\n"], "answers": ["None\n", "None\n", "None\n", "None\n"]}, {"id": 68, "question": "22. Refer to the exhibit. Considering the route map configuration for BGP, which statement describes the condition for a network prefix to match the route map TEST ?\n", "correct_answer": ["The network prefix needs to match either ACL1 or ACL2 independently of the processing action.\n"], "answers": ["The network prefix needs to match both ACL1 and ACL2 independently of the processing action.\n", "If the processing action is permit, the network prefix needs to match either ACL1 or ACL2.\n", "The network prefix needs to match either ACL1 or ACL2 independently of the processing action.\n", "If the processing action is deny, the network prefix needs to match both ACL1 and ACL2.\n"]}, {"id": 69, "question": "23. Which BGP state is the one where BGP waits for a KEEPALIVE or NOTIFICATION message from a neighbor so that the BGP session can be moved to Established?\n", "correct_answer": ["OpenConfirm\n"], "answers": ["Attempt\n", "Down\n", "OpenConfirm\n", "Init\n"]}, {"id": 70, "question": "24. Which three statements describe the weight attribute for BGP? (Choose three.)\n", "correct_answer": ["It is a Cisco-defined attribute.\n", "It is not advertised to other routers.\n", "It is a 16-bit value assigned locally on the router.\n"], "answers": ["It is a Cisco-defined attribute.\n", "It is a nontransitive attribute that uses a 32-bit value called metric.\n", "It is not advertised to other routers.\n", "It is a 16-bit value assigned locally on the router.\n", "It is not advertised between eBGP peers and is typically used to influence the next-hop address for outbound traffic.\n", "It is a well-known discretionary path attribute and is included with path advertisements throughout an AS.\n"]}, {"id": 71, "question": "25. Which BGP attribute can be configured on IBGP speakers so they will choose a desired path out of the autonomous system to an outside network?\n", "correct_answer": ["local preference\n"], "answers": ["local preference\n", "next hop\n", "MED\n", "aggregate\n"]}, {"id": 72, "question": "26. A network administrator is configuring a prefix list to match networks for BGP route filtering. Which two networks match the prefix match specification 10.224.0.0/12 ge 24 le 28 ? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["10.230.15.0/24\n", "10.239.255.240/28\n"], "answers": ["10.240.10.0/24\n", "10.224.10.0/12\n", "10.230.15.0/24\n", "10.239.255.240/28\n", "10.192.20.0/26\n"]}, {"id": 73, "question": "27. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is troubleshooting BGP configuration and wants to display only routes that originated in AS 40. Which regular expression should the administrator use in the command show bgp ipv4 unicast regex regex-pattern ?\n", "correct_answer": ["show bgp ipv4 unicast regex ^40_\n", "Explain: \n"], "answers": ["show bgp ipv4 unicast regex ^40_\n", "show bgp ipv4 unicast regex *40_\n", "show bgp ipv4 unicast regex _40$ ????\n", "show bgp ipv4 unicast regex .40.\n"]}, {"id": 74, "question": "28. Which two statements describe private BGP communities? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["A private BGP community requires a route map configuration.\n", "Private BGP communities are within the range of 0xFFFF0000 to 0xFFFFFFFF.\n", "Explain:\n"], "answers": ["A private BGP community requires a route map configuration.\n", "Private BGP communities are used to signify no transit networks.\n", "An organization needs to register for a private BGP community.\n", "Private BGP communities are within the range of 0xFFFF0000 to 0xFFFFFFFF.\n", "A private BGP community uses the first 16 bits to represent its AS and the second 16 bits to represent a pattern.\n"]}, {"id": 75, "question": "29. Refer to the exhibit. Given the above configuration commands, which two statements are true? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["RTA will set the atomic aggregate attribute to true.\n", "RTA will create the supernet route even if no other specific routes belonging to the supernet are in the route table.\n"], "answers": ["RTA will set the atomic aggregate attribute to false.\n", "RTA will set the atomic aggregate attribute to true.\n", "RTA will send the supernet route as well as all other specific BGP routes that belong to that supernet.\n", "RTA will create the supernet route even if no other specific routes belonging to the supernet are in the route table.\n", "RTA will send the supernet route and suppress the more specific routes known to BGP.\n"]}, {"id": 76, "question": "30. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator issues the show bgp ipv4 unicast command to check the routes in the BGP table. What does the indication of 0.0.0.0 under Next Hop mean?\n", "correct_answer": ["The route is originated from a connected network to the router.\n"], "answers": ["The route is the best route for the network prefix.\n", "The route is originated from a connected network to the router.\n", "The route is learned through a static route.\n", "The route is learned through IGP.\n"]}, {"id": 77, "question": "31. A network administrator is configuring route summarization for received routes before advertising to the next peer with the commands:\n", "correct_answer": ["How will the aggregate route be advertised after the commands are entered?\n", "The aggregate route will be advertised with previous BGP path information.\n"], "answers": ["The aggregate route will be advertised together with the smaller component network prefixes.\n", "The advertised aggregate route will increase the hop counts as it indicates multiple autonomous systems.\n", "The aggregate route will be advertised as an atomic aggregate route.\n", "The aggregate route will be advertised with previous BGP path information.\n"]}, {"id": 78, "question": "32. Which BGP state is the one where an Open message has been sent from the originating router and is awaiting an Open message from the other router?\n", "correct_answer": ["OpenSent\n"], "answers": ["ExStart\n", "OpenSent\n", "2-way\n", "Passive\n"]}, {"id": 79, "question": "33. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is configuring BGP route filtering on R1. The objective is to advertise only locally originated routes to its neighbor to avoid undesirable transit connectivity. Which AS path ACL should the administrator configure?\n", "correct_answer": ["ip as-path access-list 1 permit ^$\n"], "answers": ["ip as-path access-list 1 permit [^$]\n", "ip as-path access-list 1 permit *$\n", "ip as-path access-list 1 permit ^$\n", "ip as-path access-list 1 permit _$\n"]}, {"id": 80, "question": "34. A network administrator is configuring an ACL to match networks for BGP route filtering. The administrator creates an ACE permit ip 10.0.64.0 0.0.63.0 255.255.255.0 0.0.0.192 . Which two networks match the ACE? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["10.0.126.0/25\n", "10.0.64.0/24\n"], "answers": ["10.0.128.0/25\n", "10.0.126.0/25\n", "10.0.130.0/24\n", "10.0.64.0/24\n", "10.0.63.0/26\n"]}, {"id": 81, "question": "35. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator is troubleshooting BGP configuration and wants to display only routes with AS 300 being the first AS in the AS_Path value. Which regular expression should the administrator use in the command show bgp ipv4 unicast regex regex-pattern ?\n", "correct_answer": ["show bgp ipv4 unicast regex ^300_\n"], "answers": ["show bgp ipv4 unicast regex $300\n", "show bgp ipv4 unicast regex .300.\n", "show bgp ipv4 unicast regex _300_\n", "None\n"]}, {"id": 82, "question": "36. Which BGP message is sent when an error is detected with the BGP session causing the BGP connection to close?\n", "correct_answer": ["Notification\n"], "answers": ["Notification\n", "Database description\n", "Query\n", "Reply\n"]}, {"id": 83, "question": "37. Which BGP attribute is used as a loop-prevention mechanism in BGP?\n", "correct_answer": ["AS_Path\n"], "answers": ["Local Preference (LocPrf)\n", "Multiple-exit discriminator (MED)\n", "Origin\n", "AS_Path\n"]}, {"id": 84, "question": "1. What is the IP address for the Cisco-RP-announce multicast group?\n", "correct_answer": ["224.0.1.39\n"], "answers": ["224.0.1.49\n", "224.0.0.1\n", "224.0.0.40\n", "224.0.1.39\n"]}, {"id": 85, "question": "2. Which is a characteristic of PIM sparse mode?\n", "correct_answer": ["It requires an RP on the network to act as the root of the shared distribution tree.\n"], "answers": ["It uses a pruning mechanism to stop the flow of unwanted multicast traffic on interfaces with no downstream neighbors.\n", "It requires an RP on the network to act as the root of the shared distribution tree.\n", "It builds the multicast tree by flooding traffic out all interfaces.\n", "It is designed for networks where receivers are located on every subnet in the network.\n"]}, {"id": 86, "question": "3. The bootstrap router (BSR) mechanism of automating the distribution of rendezvous point (RP) information uses which IP address to disseminate information to all protocol independent multicast (PIM) routers?\n", "correct_answer": ["224.0.0.13\n"], "answers": ["224.1.0.13\n", "224.0.0.13\n", "224.1.1.13\n", "224.0.1.13\n"]}, {"id": 87, "question": "4. A network administrator is troubleshooting an IP multicast problem. Where can the administrator view source S, group G, incoming interfaces (IIF), outgoing interfaces (OIFs), and RPF neighbor information for each multicast route?\n", "correct_answer": ["in the multicast routing information base\n"], "answers": ["in unicast routing table\n", "in the routing information base\n", "in the multicast forwarding information base\n", "in the multicast routing information base\n"]}, {"id": 88, "question": "5. A network administrator statically assigns a multicast address of 239.255.8.5 to an application running on a server. The NIC on the server is with the MAC address of AB.54.C1.01.B8.9F. Which Layer 2 multicast address will receivers use on their interfaces in order to receive the multicast feed?\n", "correct_answer": ["01:00:5E:7F:08:05\n"], "answers": ["01:00:5E:01:B8:9F\n", "AB:54:C1:17:A8:02\n", "01:00:5E:7F:08:05\n", "AB:54:C1:7F:08:05\n"]}, {"id": 89, "question": "6. Which notation is used to refer to the forwarding state in PIM shared trees?\n", "correct_answer": ["(*,G)\n"], "answers": ["(*,G)\n", "(S,G)\n", "(*,S)\n", "(G,S)\n"]}, {"id": 90, "question": "7. Which statement about IGMPv3 is true?\n", "correct_answer": ["It enables a multicast receiver to signal to the first hop router the multicast sources from which it expects to receive traffic.\n"], "answers": ["It sends IGMP query messages with a TTL value of 1 addressed to the all-host group (224.0.0.1).\n", "It rejects any group-specific query message that is sent from the hosts that want to join a multicast group.\n", "It enables a multicast receiver to signal to the first hop router the multicast sources from which it expects to receive traffic.\n", "It does not accept a leave group message from the hosts that have already joined the multicast group.\n"]}, {"id": 91, "question": "8. Which well-know multicast group is joined by all PIM-enabled routers to receive RP mappings?\n", "correct_answer": ["224.0.1.40\n"], "answers": ["224.0.0.2\n", "224.0.0.13\n", "224.0.1.40\n", "224.0.1.39\n"]}, {"id": 92, "question": "9. An administrator has configured and enabled multicast together with PIM sparse mode on all VLANs on the network. Which feature helps to reduce multicast traffic being broadcast on the access layer switches?\n", "correct_answer": ["IGMP snooping\n"], "answers": ["source registration\n", "PIM Pruning\n", "IGMP snooping\n", "SPT switchover\n"]}, {"id": 93, "question": "10. Which two IGMPv3 modes are used to signal membership to a multicast host group? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["include\n", "exclude\n"], "answers": ["preclude\n", "join\n", "include\n", "rendezvous\n", "exclude\n", "leave\n"]}, {"id": 94, "question": "11. Which statement describes a characteristic of IP multicast routing?\n", "correct_answer": ["PIM dense mode flood and prune behavior repeats every three minutes.\n"], "answers": ["PIM hello messages are sent every 60 seconds by default out each PIM enabled interface.\n", "PIM dense mode flood and prune behavior repeats every three minutes.\n", "PIM sparse mode builds the multicast tree through flooding of traffic out every interface.\n", "PIM sparse mode and PIM dense mode require an RP on the network.\n"]}, {"id": 95, "question": "12. To which multicast group does a candidate RP send announcement messages to advertise its willingness to be an RP?\n", "correct_answer": ["224.0.1.39\n"], "answers": ["224.0.0.13\n", "224.0.1.40\n", "224.0.1.39\n", "224.0.0.2\n"]}, {"id": 96, "question": "13. Which two statements about Protocol Independent Multicast (PIM) are true? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["Three of the forwarding modes for PIM are PIM dense mode (PIM-DM), PIM sparse mode (PIM-SM), and PIM sparse-dense mode.\n", "PIM is a multicast routing protocol that makes packet-forwarding decisions independent of the unicast IP routing protocol that is running in the network.\n"], "answers": ["Three of the forwarding modes for PIM are PIM dense mode (PIM-DM), PIM sparse mode (PIM-SM), and PIM sparse-dense mode.\n", "PIM is a multicast routing protocol that makes packet-forwarding decisions independent of the unicast IP routing protocol that is running in the network.\n", "PIM should be configured on the device that hosts the source of the muticast traffic.\n", "PIM sparse mode is most useful when there are few senders, many receivers, and the volume of multicast traffic is high.\n", "PIM should be configured only on the first and the last hop routers in the multicast tree.\n", "PIM does not require an IGP protocol to be configured in the network.\n"]}, {"id": 97, "question": "14. Which two statements describe IGMP? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["IGMPv3 provides support for SSM.\n", "Multicast flooding on a LAN segment can be mitigated by using IGMP snooping.\n"], "answers": ["IGMPv2 supports multicast source filtering.\n", "IGMPv1 only supports queries sent to a predefined group.\n", "IGMPv3 provides support for SSM.\n", "An IGMPv2 router will only allow IGMPv2 hosts to execute a join request.\n", "Multicast flooding on a LAN segment can be mitigated by using IGMP snooping.\n"]}, {"id": 98, "question": "15. Which nonproprietary mechanism does PIM use to discover and announce RP set information for each group prefix for all the routers in a PIM domain?\n", "correct_answer": ["BSR\n"], "answers": ["Static RP\n", "BSR\n", "RPF\n", "Auto-RP\n"]}, {"id": 99, "question": "16. What happens when an edge router using IntServ QoS determines that the data pathway cannot support the level of QoS requested?\n", "correct_answer": ["Data is not forwarded along the pathway.\n"], "answers": ["Data is forwarded along the pathway using IntServ but not provided preferential treatment.\n", "Data is forwarded along the pathway using DiffServ.\n", "Data is forwarded along the pathway using a best-effort approach.\n", "Data is not forwarded along the pathway.\n"]}, {"id": 100, "question": "17. Question as presented: Match the state with its marking in a DSCP two token bucket mechanism environment. (Not all options apply.)\n", "correct_answer": ["Exceed\n", "Confrom\n", "Violate\n"], "answers": ["Exceed\n", "Confrom\n", "Violate\n"]}, {"id": 101, "question": "18. What two fields are available in IPv4 and IPv6 headers to mark packets for QoS? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["Traffic Class\n", "Type of Service\n"], "answers": ["Traffic Class\n", "Class of Service\n", "Type of Service\n", "Priority\n", "VLAN ID\n"]}, {"id": 102, "question": "19. A network administrator has defined the trust boundary of a network. What is the function of trusted endpoints deployed across the network?\n", "correct_answer": ["Trusted endpoints have the ability to mark application traffic.\n"], "answers": ["Trusted endpoints are devices designed to provide network security features.\n", "Trusted endpoints provide monitoring and logging solutions.\n", "Trusted endpoints have the ability to mark application traffic.\n", "Trusted endpoints provide the ability to drop previously marked traffic during congestions.\n"]}, {"id": 103, "question": "20. Which is a QoS model that a network engineer would implement to ensure a source to destination quality of service standard for a specified data flow?\n", "correct_answer": ["integrated services\n"], "answers": ["best effort\n", "low latency queuing\n", "differentiated services\n", "class-based weighted fair queuing\n", "integrated services\n"]}, {"id": 104, "question": "21. What would be the Tc value in ms for a 1 Gbps interface configured with a policer defined with a CIR of 150 Mbps and a Bc of 12 Mb?\n", "correct_answer": ["100 ms\n"], "answers": ["10,000 ms\n", "1000 ms\n", "100 ms\n", "10 ms\n"]}, {"id": 105, "question": "22. What statement describes the Class of Service field?\n", "correct_answer": ["It is a Layer 2 field.\n"], "answers": ["It is a Layer 2 field.\n", "It is a field that is 6 bits long.\n", "It is a field that is 8 bits long.\n", "It is a Layer 1 field.\n"]}, {"id": 106, "question": "23. Which protocol operates at Layer 3 and is used for marking packets?\n", "correct_answer": ["DSCP\n"], "answers": ["CoS\n", "IntServ\n", "DSCP\n", "QoE\n"]}, {"id": 107, "question": "24. What is the recommended maximum one-way latency when implementing video over IP for real-time video applications?\n", "correct_answer": ["The recommended maximum one-way latency should not be more than 150 ms.\n"], "answers": ["Latency is not a factor for smooth video over IP implementation.\n", "Latency should be defined for voice traffic only (not for video).\n", "The recommended maximum one-way latency should not be more than 150 ms.\n", "When mixed video and voice packets are included in the video stream, the latency should be 300 ms.\n"]}, {"id": 108, "question": "25. Which two procedures should be implemented when deploying VoIP in a campus network? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["packet marking for voice traffic with a 802.1p CoS value of 5\n", "a voice class low-latency queuing (LLQ) QoS policy\n"], "answers": ["voice and data traffic in the same VLAN and mark the traffic for high priority treatment\n", "a traffic shaping QoS policy to guarantee minimum delay for the voice traffic\n", "packet marking for voice traffic with a 802.1p CoS value of 5\n", "priority queuing with voice traffic given the high-priority queue\n", "a voice class low-latency queuing (LLQ) QoS policy\n"]}, {"id": 109, "question": "26. Which statement is true about the Single-Rate Two-Color Markers algorithm?\n", "correct_answer": ["It uses a single token bucket algorithm and traffic can be marked or dropped in both states (conforming to or exceeding the CIR).\n"], "answers": ["It uses a two bucket algorithm and traffic can be classified as conforming to, exceeding, or violating the CIR.\n", "It uses a single token bucket algorithm and traffic can be marked or dropped in both states (conforming to or exceeding the CIR).\n", "It uses a two bucket algorithm that causes fewer TCP transmissions and is more efficient for bandwidth utilization.\n", "It uses a single bucket algorithm and uses three colors or states to classify the traffic.\n"]}, {"id": 110, "question": "27. Question as presented: Match the queuing algorithm with its description. (Not all options apply.)\n", "correct_answer": ["CBWFQ\n", "LLQ\n", "WFQ\n", "PQ\n", "Round Robin\n"], "answers": ["CBWFQ\n", "LLQ\n", "WFQ\n", "PQ\n", "Round Robin\n"]}, {"id": 111, "question": "28. What is the value of the DSCP marker for video traffic on a WLAN?\n", "correct_answer": ["AF41\n"], "answers": ["AF41\n", "O\n", "AF11\n", "EF\n"]}, {"id": 112, "question": "29. Which statement describes NBAR2?\n", "correct_answer": ["NBAR2 uses MQC to match traffic to specific protocols.\n"], "answers": ["NBAR2 can identify a variety of protocols and applications by using up to Layer 6 data.\n", "NBAR2 supports only scavenger traffic.\n", "NBAR2 uses MQC to match traffic to specific protocols.\n", "NBAR2 does not require monthly protocol packs to identify new and emerging applications.\n"]}, {"id": 113, "question": "30. Match QoS techniques with the description. (Not all options are used.)\n", "correct_answer": ["traffic shaping\n", "traffic policing\n", "classification\n", "marking\n", "None\n"], "answers": ["traffic shaping\n", "traffic policing\n", "classification\n", "marking\n", "None\n"]}, {"id": 114, "question": "31. Match the parameter with the correct description. (Not all options apply.)\n", "correct_answer": ["CoS\n", "Tc\n", "CIR\n"], "answers": ["CoS\n", "Tc\n", "CIR\n"]}, {"id": 115, "question": "32. Match the operation to the appropriate QoS model.\n", "correct_answer": ["QoS is not for this model\n", "No packets receive preferential treatement\n", "End-to-end QoS is provided\n", "Network resources are requested\n", "Network device are setu to handle multiple traffic classes\n", "Traffic is identied in classes based on business requirement"], "answers": ["QoS is not for this model\n", "No packets receive preferential treatement\n", "End-to-end QoS is provided\n", "Network resources are requested\n", "Network device are setu to handle multiple traffic classes\n", "Traffic is identied in classes based on business requirement"]}, {"id": 116, "question": "1. Refer to the exhibit. Based on the output that is shown, what type of NAT has been implemented?\n", "correct_answer": ["PAT using an external interface\n"], "answers": ["dynamic NAT with a pool of two public IP addresses\n", "static NAT with a NAT pool\n", "PAT using an external interface\n", "static NAT with one entry\n"]}, {"id": 117, "question": "2. Match the steps with the actions that are involved when an internal host with IP address 192.168.10.10 attempts to send a packet to an external server at the IP address 209.165.200.254 across a router R1 that is running dynamic NAT. (Not all options are used.)\n", "correct_answer": ["None\n", "step 5\n", "step 2\n", "step 4\n", "step 1\n", "step 3\n"], "answers": ["None\n", "step 5\n", "step 2\n", "step 4\n", "step 1\n", "step 3\n"]}, {"id": 118, "question": "3. Refer to the exhibit. What has to be done in order to complete the static NAT configuration on R1?\n", "correct_answer": ["Interface S0/0/0 should be configured with the command ip nat outside .\n"], "answers": ["R1 should be configured with the command ip nat inside source static 209.165.200.200 192.168.11.11 .\n", "None\n", "Interface Fa0/0 should be configured with the command no ip nat inside .\n", "R1 should be configured with the command ip nat inside source static 209.165.200.1 192.168.11.11 .\n"]}, {"id": 119, "question": "4. Refer to the exhibit. Given the commands as shown, how many hosts on the internal LAN off R1 can have simultaneous NAT translations on R1?\n", "correct_answer": ["1\n"], "answers": ["1\n", "255\n", "244\n", "10\n"]}, {"id": 120, "question": "5. What is a potential disadvantage when implementing HSRP as compared to GLBP?\n", "correct_answer": ["HSRP does not provide load balancing with multiple active routers.\n"], "answers": ["HSRP does not provide load balancing with multiple active routers.\n", "HSRP does not function in a multivendor environment.\n", "HSRP does not have the capability to support IPv6 addresses.\n", "HSRP provides default gateway failover only when the active router fails.\n"]}, {"id": 121, "question": "6. What are three advantages of using private IP addresses and NAT? (Choose three.)\n", "correct_answer": ["hides private LAN addressing from outside devices that are connected to the Internet\n", "conserves registered public IP addresses\n", "permits LAN expansion without additional public IP addresses\n"], "answers": ["creates multiple public IP addresses\n", "reduces CPU usage on customer routers\n", "hides private LAN addressing from outside devices that are connected to the Internet\n", "improves the performance of the router that is connected to the Internet\n", "conserves registered public IP addresses\n", "permits LAN expansion without additional public IP addresses\n"]}, {"id": 122, "question": "7. A network engineer wants to synchronize the time of a router with an NTP server at the IPv4 address 209.165.200.225. The exit interface of the router is configured with an IPv4 address of 192.168.212.11. Which global configuration command should be used to configure the NTP server as the time source for this router?\n", "correct_answer": ["ntp server 209.165.200.225\n"], "answers": ["ntp peer 209.165.200.225\n", "ntp peer 192.168.212.11\n", "ntp server 192.168.212.11\n", "ntp server 209.165.200.225\n"]}, {"id": 123, "question": "8. Which router command is required to configure VRRP to support IPv6?\n", "correct_answer": ["fhrp version vrrp v3\n"], "answers": ["standby 1 ipv6 FE80::1:1\n", "fhrp version vrrp v3\n", "standby 6 ipv6 autoconfig\n", "vrrp 22 address-family ipv6\n"]}, {"id": 124, "question": "9. A networking engineer is configuring an NTP client to have access to multiple NTP servers but wants one server to have priority over the others. Which command will achieve this?\n", "correct_answer": ["ntp server 203.0.113.1 prefer\n"], "answers": ["ntp server 2001:DB8:0:0:800:200C:417A version 4h\n", "ntp max-associations 1\n", "ntp server 203.0.113.1 prefer\n", "ntp master 1\n"]}, {"id": 125, "question": "10. What is a feature or purpose of NTP peers?\n", "correct_answer": ["NTP peers query each other to synchronize their clocks.\n"], "answers": ["NTP peers are NTP clients that share a common NTP server.\n", "An NTP client that loses connection with an NTP server can synchronize the time with an NTP peer.\n", "NTP peers query each other to synchronize their clocks.\n", "An NTP peer that loses connection with another NTP peer loses all NTP synchronization.\n"]}, {"id": 126, "question": "11. Which two NTP details are displayed by issuing the show ntp associations command on a switch configured to use NTP? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["NTP server IP address\n", "reference clock IP address\n"], "answers": ["reference time\n", "NTP server IP address\n", "reference clock IP address\n", "\u201cClock is synchronized\u201d statement\n", "NTP uptime\n"]}, {"id": 127, "question": "12. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator has configured R2 for PAT. Why is the configuration incorrect?\n", "correct_answer": ["NAT-POOL2 is bound to the wrong ACL.\n"], "answers": ["The overload keyword should not have been applied.\n", "The ACL does not define the list of addresses to be translated.\n", "The static NAT entry is missing.\n", "NAT-POOL2 is bound to the wrong ACL.\n"]}, {"id": 128, "question": "13. Refer to the exhibit. NAT is configured on RT1 and RT2. The PC is sending a request to the web server. What IPv4 address is the source IP address in the packet between RT2 and the web server?\n", "correct_answer": ["209.165.200.245\n"], "answers": ["192.0.2.2\n", "172.16.1.10\n", "172.16.1.254\n", "209.165.200.245\n", "203.0.113.10\n", "192.168.1.5\n"]}, {"id": 129, "question": "14. A network administrator would like to ensure that router R1 is always elected the active router for an HSRP group. Which set of commands would ensure the required results?\n", "correct_answer": ["R1(config-if)# ip address 192.168.1.100 255.255.255.0\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 ip 192.168.1.1\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 priority 255\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 preempt\n", "R1(config-if)# no shutdown\n"], "answers": ["R1(config-if)# ip address 192.168.1.100 255.255.255.0\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 ip 192.168.1.1\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 priority 150\n", "R1(config-if)# no shutdown\n", "//\n", "R1(config-if)# ip address 192.168.1.250 255.255.255.0\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 ip 192.168.1.1\n", "R1(config-if)# no shutdown\n", "//\n", "R1(config-if)# ip address 192.168.1.100 255.255.255.0\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 ip 192.168.1.1\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 priority 1\n", "R1(config-if)# no shutdown\n", "//\n", "R1(config-if)# ip address 192.168.1.100 255.255.255.0\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 ip 192.168.1.1\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 priority 255\n", "R1(config-if)# standby 1 preempt\n", "R1(config-if)# no shutdown\n"]}, {"id": 130, "question": "15. Refer to the exhibit. What two statements describe the NTP status of the router? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["The router is attached to a stratum 2 device.\n", "The IP address of the time source for the router is 192.168.1.1.\n"], "answers": ["The router is serving as an authoritative time source.\n", "The software clock for the router must be configured with the set clock command so that NTP will function properly.\n", "The router is attached to a stratum 2 device.\n", "The router is serving as a time source for the device at 192.168.1.1.\n", "The IP address of the time source for the router is 192.168.1.1.\n"]}, {"id": 131, "question": "16. Refer to the exhibit. A network administrator has just configured address translation and is verifying the configuration. What three things can the administrator verify? (Choose three.)\n", "correct_answer": ["A standard access list numbered 1 was used as part of the configuration process.\n", "Two types of NAT are enabled.\n", "Address translation is working.\n"], "answers": ["A standard access list numbered 1 was used as part of the configuration process.\n", "Two types of NAT are enabled.\n", "One port on the router is not participating in the address translation.\n", "Address translation is working.\n", "Three addresses from the NAT pool are being used by hosts.\n", "The name of the NAT pool is refCount.\n"]}, {"id": 132, "question": "17. Refer to the exhibit. What statement is true about the output of the show standby command?\n", "correct_answer": ["The router is currently forwarding packets.\n"], "answers": ["The router is currently forwarding packets.\n", "This router is tracking two properly operating interfaces.\n", "The current priority of this router is 120.\n", "This router is in the HSRP down state because its tracked interfaces are down.\n"]}, {"id": 133, "question": "18. Match the step number to the sequence of stages that occur during the HSRP failover process. (Not all options are used.)\n", "correct_answer": ["step 4\n", "None\n", "step 3\n", "step 1\n", "step 2\n"], "answers": ["step 4\n", "None\n", "step 3\n", "step 1\n", "step 2\n"]}, {"id": 134, "question": "19. Refer to the exhibit. An organization has two remote sites which are connected by a GRE tunnel through an ISP cloud network. The organization has two routers (CPE1 and CPE2) at each of the remote sites which connect to the ISP routers, SP1 and SP2. Which two nodes are the GRE tunnel endpoints to connect the two remote sites? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["CPE1\n", "CPE2\n"], "answers": ["Host A\n", "CPE1\n", "SP1\n", "SP2\n", "CPE2\n", "Host B\n"]}, {"id": 135, "question": "20. Which protocol creates a virtual point-to-point connection to tunnel unencrypted traffic between Cisco routers from a variety of protocols?\n", "correct_answer": ["GRE\n"], "answers": ["GRE\n", "IKE\n", "OSPF\n", "IPsec\n"]}, {"id": 136, "question": "21. How many bytes of overhead are added to each IP packet while it is transported through a GRE tunnel?\n", "correct_answer": ["24\n"], "answers": ["8\n", "32\n", "16\n", "24\n"]}, {"id": 137, "question": "22. Refer to the exhibit. Which IP address is configured on the physical interface of the CORP router?\n", "correct_answer": ["209.165.202.133\n"], "answers": ["10.1.1.2\n", "209.165.202.134\n", "209.165.202.133\n", "10.1.1.1\n"]}, {"id": 138, "question": "23. What is an IPsec protocol that provides data confidentiality and authentication for IP packets?\n", "correct_answer": ["ESP\n"], "answers": ["IKE\n", "RSA\n", "ESP\n", "AH\n"]}, {"id": 139, "question": "24. What two encryption algorithms are used in IPsec VPNs? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["3DES\n", "AES\n"], "answers": ["PSK\n", "3DES\n", "IKE\n", "DH\n", "AES\n"]}, {"id": 140, "question": "25. Which two identification methods are used by LISP instead of traditional IP addresses? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["RLOCs\n", "EIDs\n"], "answers": ["xTR\n", "RLOCs\n", "MRs\n", "PxTRs\n", "EIDs\n"]}, {"id": 141, "question": "26. Which LISP header is used to provide a secure boundary between multiple organizations?\n", "correct_answer": ["Instance ID\n"], "answers": ["outer LISP UDP header\n", "outer LISP IP header\n", "Instance ID\n", "RLOC\n"]}, {"id": 142, "question": "27. How is routing handled within a LISP site?\n", "correct_answer": ["through the use of an interior routing protocol\n"], "answers": ["through the use of virtual tunnels\n", "through the use of virtual controllers\n", "through the use of an interior routing protocol\n", "through the use of RLOCs\n"]}, {"id": 143, "question": "28. What is the purpose of a VNI when a company is using VXLANs?\n", "correct_answer": ["to uniquely identify overlay networks\n"], "answers": ["to map Layer 2 to Layer 3 packets\n", "to facilitate the discovery of underlay Layer 3 networks\n", "to uniquely identify overlay networks\n", "to create a database of EID-to-RLOC mappings\n"]}, {"id": 144, "question": "29. What is the purpose of VTEPs when using VXLANs?\n", "correct_answer": ["originate or terminate tunnels\n"], "answers": ["propagate map replies to end devices\n", "originate or terminate tunnels\n", "identify virtual segments within an organization\n", "provide replies to internal devices when an external device is cloud-based\n"]}, {"id": 145, "question": "30. What are three characteristics of the generic routing encapsulation (GRE) protocol? (Choose three.)\n", "correct_answer": ["By default, GRE does not include any flow control mechanisms.\n", "GRE tunnels support multicast traffic.\n", "GRE creates additional overhead for packets that are traveling through the VPN.\n"], "answers": ["Developed by the IETF, GRE is a secure tunneling protocol that was designed for Cisco routers.\n", "By default, GRE does not include any flow control mechanisms.\n", "GRE provides encapsulation for a single protocol type that is traveling through the VPN.\n", "GRE tunnels support multicast traffic.\n", "GRE uses AES for encryption unless otherwise specified.\n", "GRE creates additional overhead for packets that are traveling through the VPN.\n"]}, {"id": 146, "question": "31. By the use of sequence numbers, which function of the IPsec security services prevents spoofing by verifying that each packet is non-duplicated and unique?\n", "correct_answer": ["anti-replay protection\n"], "answers": ["anti-replay protection\n", "confidentiality\n", "authentication\n", "data integrity\n"]}, {"id": 147, "question": "32. Match the LISP term to the definition. (Not all options are used.)\n", "correct_answer": ["EID\n", "RLOC\n", "None\n", "MS\n", "MR\n"], "answers": ["EID\n", "RLOC\n", "None\n", "MS\n", "MR\n"]}, {"id": 148, "question": "33. What is the purpose of a proxy ETR used with LISP?\n", "correct_answer": ["to communicate with a non-LISP site\n"], "answers": ["to communicate with a non-LISP site\n", "to send map request packets to the MR on behalf of an ETR\n", "to perform a DNS lookup for any EID within an LISP site\n", "to register any EID addresses that are not within the mapping database\n"]}, {"id": 149, "question": "34. Which algorithm is considered insecure for use in IPsec encryption?\n", "correct_answer": ["3DES\n"], "answers": ["AES\n", "3DES\n", "SHA-1\n", "RSA\n"]}, {"id": 150, "question": "35. Refer to the exhibit. What algorithm is being used to provide public key exchange?\n", "correct_answer": ["Diffie-Hellman\n"], "answers": ["SHA\n", "RSA\n", "Diffie-Hellman\n", "AES\n"]}, {"id": 151, "question": "36. What is the first step in establishing an IPsec VPN?\n", "correct_answer": ["detection of interesting traffic\n"], "answers": ["creation of a secure tunnel to negotiate a security association policy\n", "detection of interesting traffic\n", "negotiation of ISAKMP policies\n", "creation of an IPsec tunnel between two IPsec peers\n"]}, {"id": 152, "question": "1. Which type of routing protocol uses LSAs and TLVs to support extended features?\n", "correct_answer": ["link-state\n"], "answers": ["path vector\n", "link-state\n", "hybrid\n", "distance vector\n"]}, {"id": 153, "question": "2. What are two characteristics of link-state routing protocols? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["They provide routers with a synchronized identical map of the network.\n", "They use more CPU and memory resources than distance vector protocols do.\n"], "answers": ["They can load balance across unequal metric cost paths.\n", "They use path attributes to determine the best loop-free path.\n", "They periodically send full routing table updates to directly connected neighbors.\n", "They provide routers with a synchronized identical map of the network.\n", "They use more CPU and memory resources than distance vector protocols do.\n"]}, {"id": 154, "question": "3. What data is used by OSPF and ISIS for loop prevention?\n", "correct_answer": ["a synchronized map of the network\n"], "answers": ["hop count to the destination\n", "feasible distance calculation to the destination\n", "autonomous system path to the destination\n", "a synchronized map of the network\n"]}, {"id": 155, "question": "4. Which routing protocol incorporates characteristics of both distance vector and link-state protocols?\n", "correct_answer": ["EIGRP\n"], "answers": ["iBGP\n", "EBGP\n", "SIS\n", "EIGRP\n"]}, {"id": 156, "question": "5. How do EIGRP routers establish and maintain neighbor relationships?\n", "correct_answer": ["by exchanging hello packets with neighboring routers\n"], "answers": ["by exchanging routing tables with directly attached routers\n", "by exchanging neighbor tables with directly attached routers\n", "by comparing known routes to information received in updates\n", "by dynamically learning new routes from neighbors\n", "by exchanging hello packets with neighboring routers\n"]}, {"id": 157, "question": "6. A router has installed several routes into the routing table. How will the router determine which route to use to forward packets?\n", "correct_answer": ["the longest prefix match\n"], "answers": ["the lowest administrative distance\n", "the highest metric\n", "the lowest metric\n", "the longest prefix match\n"]}, {"id": 158, "question": "7. What is the effect of configuring the ipv6 unicast-routing command on a router?\n", "correct_answer": ["to enable the router as an IPv6 router\n"], "answers": ["to assign the router to the all-nodes multicast group\n", "to permit only unicast packets on the router\n", "to enable the router as an IPv6 router\n", "to prevent the router from joining the all-routers multicast group\n"]}, {"id": 159, "question": "8. Why would a floating static route be configured with an administrative distance that is higher than the administrative distance of a dynamic routing protocol that is running on the same router?\n", "correct_answer": ["to be used as a backup route\n"], "answers": ["to load-balance the traffic\n", "to act as a gateway of last resort\n", "to be used as a backup route\n", "to be the priority route in the routing table\n"]}, {"id": 160, "question": "9. Which static route statement shows a recursive IPv6 static route?\n", "correct_answer": ["ipv6 route 2001:db8:cafe:1::/56 2001:db8:1000:10::1\n"], "answers": ["ipv6 route 2001:db8:cafe:1::/56 S0/0/0\n", "ipv6 route 0::/0 S0/0/0\n", "ipv6 route 0::/0 S0/0/0 254\n", "ipv6 route 2001:db8:cafe:1::/56 S0/0/0 2001:db8:1000:10::1\n", "ipv6 route 2001:db8:cafe:1::/56 2001:db8:1000:10::1\n"]}, {"id": 161, "question": "10. Refer to the exhibit. Which command will properly configure an IPv6 static route on R2 that will allow traffic from PC2 to reach PC1 without any recursive lookups by router R2?\n", "correct_answer": ["R2(config)# ipv6 route 2001:db8:10:12::/64 S0/0/0\n"], "answers": ["R2(config)# ipv6 route 2001:db8:10:12::/64 S0/0/0\n", "R2(config)# ipv6 route ::/0 2001:db8:32::1\n", "R2(config)# ipv6 route 2001:db8:10:12::/64 S0/0/1\n", "R2(config)# ipv6 route 2001:db8:10:12::/64 2001:db8:32::1\n"]}, {"id": 162, "question": "11. Refer to the exhibit. Router R1 has an OSPF neighbor relationship with the ISP router over the 192.168.0.32 network. The 192.168.0.36 network link should serve as a backup when the OSPF link goes down. The floating static route command ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 S0/0/1 100 was issued on R1 and now traffic is using the backup link even when the OSPF link is up and functioning. Which change should be made to the static route command so that traffic will only use the OSPF link when it is up?\u200b\n", "correct_answer": ["Change the administrative distance to 120.\n"], "answers": ["Add the next hop neighbor address of 192.168.0.36.\n", "Change the administrative distance to 1.\n", "Change the destination network to 192.168.0.34.\n", "Change the administrative distance to 120.\n"]}, {"id": 163, "question": "12. What is used by BGP to guarantee a loop free path to reach a destination?\n", "correct_answer": ["a record of each autonomous system that a routing advertisement has traversed\n"], "answers": ["the count of router hops to reach a destination\n", "the cumulative cost as measured in bandwidth\n", "a record of each autonomous system that a routing advertisement has traversed\n", "a distance calculation based on cumulative delay and minimum bandwidth\n"]}, {"id": 164, "question": "13. What is the purpose for creating VRFs on a router?\n", "correct_answer": ["to isolate paths\n"], "answers": ["to isolate paths\n", "to determine the vector to reach a destination network\n", "to prevent routing loops\n", "to keep a record of all autonomous systems that routing advertisements have traversed\n"]}, {"id": 165, "question": "14. Which technology creates segmentation between network interfaces, IP addresses, and routing tables?\n", "correct_answer": ["virtual routing and forwarding\n"], "answers": ["virtual routing and forwarding\n", "virtual LANs\n", "multiprotocol label switching\n", "virtual router redundancy protocol\n"]}, {"id": 166, "question": "15. Refer to a portion of an EIGRP topology table: What is the reported distance of the successor route for 172.18.3.0/24?\n", "correct_answer": ["28160\n"], "answers": ["2684416\n", "2172416\n", "2072316\n", "28160\n"]}, {"id": 167, "question": "16. What is the administrative distance of a directly connected interface?\n", "correct_answer": ["0\n"], "answers": ["None\n", "5\n", "0\n", "1\n"]}, {"id": 168, "question": "17. Refer to the exhibit. R2 has two possible paths to the 192.168.10.4 network. What would make the alternate route meet the feasibility condition?\n", "correct_answer": ["a reported distance less than 3523840\n"], "answers": ["a feasible distance greater than 41024000\n", "a reported distance less than 3523840\n", "an administrative distance less than 170\n", "a reported distance greater than 41024000\n"]}, {"id": 169, "question": "18. Which protocol number is used to indicate that an EIGRP packet is encapsulated in an IP packet?\n", "correct_answer": ["88\n"], "answers": ["6\n", "17\n", "88\n", "89\n"]}, {"id": 170, "question": "19. Match the description to the EIGRP packet type. (Not all options are used.)\n", "correct_answer": ["use for\n", "used to\n", "sent in\n"], "answers": ["None\n", "None\n", "None\n", "None\n", "None\n"]}, {"id": 171, "question": "20. Which statement describes the autonomous system number used in EIGRP configuration on a Cisco router?\n", "correct_answer": ["It functions as a process ID in the operation of the router.\n"], "answers": ["It carries the geographical information of the organization.\n", "It is a globally unique autonomous system number that is assigned by IANA.\n", "It functions as a process ID in the operation of the router.\n", "It identifies the ISP that provides the connection to network of the organization.\n"]}, {"id": 172, "question": "21. Which bandwidth value is used when calculating the EIGRP metric of a route?\n", "correct_answer": ["the slowest bandwidth of all outgoing interfaces between the source and destination\n"], "answers": ["the slowest bandwidth of all outgoing interfaces between the source and destination\n", "the slowest bandwidth of all interfaces on the router\n", "the fastest bandwidth of all interfaces on the router\n", "the fastest bandwidth of all outgoing interfaces between the source and destination\n"]}, {"id": 173, "question": "22. Refer to the exhibit. All the routers that are displayed are part of the EIGRP domain. Assuming EIGRP metric weights are not altered in the configurations, which path will a packet take that originates from a host on the 192.168.1.0/24 network and is going to a host on the 192.168.2.0/24 network?\n", "correct_answer": ["R1, R2, R5, R3\n"], "answers": ["R1, R2, R3\n", "R1, R5, R3\n", "R1, R4, R3\n", "R1, R2, R5, R3\n"]}, {"id": 174, "question": "23. Which two metric weights are set to one by default when costs in EIGRP are being calculated? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["k3\n", "k1\n"], "answers": ["k6\n", "k3\n", "k1\n", "k4\n", "k5\n", "k2\n"]}, {"id": 175, "question": "24. Which routing protocol supports load balancing across links with unequal costs?\n", "correct_answer": ["EIGRP\n"], "answers": ["OSPFv2\n", "OSPFv3\n", "EIGRP\n", "RIPv2\n"]}, {"id": 176, "question": "25. How has the EIGRP routing protocol improved by having interface delay measured in picoseconds instead of microseconds?\n", "correct_answer": ["It provides better metrics for high speed interfaces.\n"], "answers": ["It allows for a larger number of networks.\n", "It speeds up convergence.\n", "It improves performance and communication time between directly connected neighbor routers.\n", "It provides better metrics for high speed interfaces.\n"]}, {"id": 177, "question": "26. If all router Ethernet interfaces in an EIGRP network are configured with the default EIGRP timers, how long will a router wait by default to receive an EIGRP packet from its neighbor before declaring the neighbor unreachable?\n", "correct_answer": ["15 seconds\n"], "answers": ["10 seconds\n", "15 seconds\n", "20 seconds\n", "30 seconds\n"]}, {"id": 178, "question": "27. What two conditions will result in an EIGRP route going into the active state? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["The successor is down.\n", "There is no feasible successor.\n"], "answers": ["The router is not sending queries.\n", "The successor is down.\n", "The network has been recalculated.\n", "There is no feasible successor.\n", "One neighbor has not met the feasibility condition.\n"]}, {"id": 179, "question": "28. An EIGRP router loses the route to a network. Its topology table contains two feasible successors to the same network. What action will the router take?\n", "correct_answer": ["The best alternative backup route is immediately inserted into the routing table.\n"], "answers": ["The router will query neighbors for an alternate route.\n", "The best alternative backup route is immediately inserted into the routing table.\n", "The router uses the default route.\n", "The DUAL algorithm is recomputed to find an alternate route.\n"]}, {"id": 180, "question": "29. Which feature of the EIGRP routing protocol can provide fast re-convergence without DUAL recomputation in the event of a route failure?\n", "correct_answer": ["having a feasible successor route\n"], "answers": ["having a route in the active state\n", "having a successor route\n", "having a feasible successor route\n", "having a route in the passive state\n"]}, {"id": 181, "question": "30. What are two benefits of applying summarization to networks within a company that uses the EIGRP routing protocol? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["reduced impact when a route goes active\n", "reduced size of routing tables\n"], "answers": ["reduced impact when a route goes active\n", "reduced number of routers that must maintain a neighbor adjacency\n", "reduced number of Layer 3 switches required\n", "reduced number of hops the packet must travel throughout the network\n", "reduced size of routing tables\n"]}, {"id": 182, "question": "31. Refer to a portion of an EIGRP topology table: What is the metric for the successor route for 10.34.1.0/24?\n", "correct_answer": ["3072\n"], "answers": ["2937\n", "2495120\n", "3072\n", "227692\n"]}, {"id": 183, "question": "32. What is the administrative distance of a static route?\n", "correct_answer": ["1\n"], "answers": ["5\n", "1\n", "20\n", "0\n"]}, {"id": 184, "question": "33. Refer to a portion of an EIGRP topology table: What is the metric for the feasible successor route for 10.34.1.0/24?\n", "correct_answer": ["5376\n"], "answers": ["3072\n", "2495120\n", "5376\n", "2937\n"]}, {"id": 185, "question": "34. What is the administrative distance of an EIGRP summary route?\n", "correct_answer": ["5\n"], "answers": ["110\n", "5\n", "90\n", "20\n"]}, {"id": 186, "question": "35. What is the administrative distance of an IS-IS route?\n", "correct_answer": ["115\n"], "answers": ["0\n", "5\n", "1\n", "115\n"]}, {"id": 187, "question": "1. What is the function of the OSPF LSR packet?\n", "correct_answer": ["It is used by the receiving routers to request more information about any entry in the LSDB.\n"], "answers": ["It is used to confirm the receipt of LSUs.\n", "It is used to establish and maintain adjacency with other OSPF routers.\n", "It is used to check the database synchronization between routers.\n", "It is used by the receiving routers to request more information about any entry in the LSDB.\n"]}, {"id": 188, "question": "2. What are two characteristics of OSPF areas? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["Area 0 is called the backbone area.\n", "All OSPF areas must be directly connected to Area 0.\n"], "answers": ["Area 0 is called the backbone area.\n", "Each OSPF area must be configured with a loopback interface.\n", "All OSPF areas must be directly connected to Area 0.\n", "All OSPF networks require the use of multiple areas.\n", "OSPF areas create a three-layer hierarchical design.\n", "Single area OSPF networks must be configured in Area 1.\n"]}, {"id": 189, "question": "3. Which three requirements are necessary for two OSPFv2 routers to form an adjacency? (Choose three.)\n", "correct_answer": ["The OSPF hello or dead timers on each router must match.\n", "The link interface subnet masks must match.\n", "The two routers must include the inter-router link network in an OSPFv2 network command.\n"], "answers": ["The OSPF hello or dead timers on each router must match.\n", "The link interface subnet masks must match.\n", "The OSPFv2 process ID must be the same on each router.\n", "The two routers must include the inter-router link network in an OSPFv2 network command.\n", "The OSPFv2 process is enabled on the interface by entering the ospf process area-id command.\n", "The link interface on each router must be configured with a link-local address.\n"]}, {"id": 190, "question": "4. A network technician issues the following commands when configuring a router: What does the number 11 represent?\n", "correct_answer": ["the OSPF process ID on R1\n"], "answers": ["the OSPF process ID on R1\n", "the administrative distance that is manually assigned to R1\n", "the area number where R1 is located\n", "the autonomous system number to which R1 belongs\n", "the cost of the link to R1\n"]}, {"id": 191, "question": "5. Refer to the exhibit. When OSPF is operational and converged, what neighbor relationship is developed between router R1 and router R2?\n", "correct_answer": ["A FULL adjacency is formed.\n"], "answers": ["A FULL adjacency is formed.\n", "Both routers will become DROTHERS.\n", "A 2WAY adjacency is formed.\n", "Router R2 will become the DR and router R1 will become the BDR.\n"]}, {"id": 192, "question": "6. Refer to the exhibit. What destination address will RTB use to advertise LSAs?\n", "correct_answer": ["224.0.0.6\n"], "answers": ["10.1.7.17\n", "224.0.0.6\n", "224.0.0.5\n", "255.255.255.255\n", "172.16.1.1\n", "172.16.2.1\n"]}, {"id": 193, "question": "7. A network administrator is implementing OSPF in a portion of the network and must ensure that only specific routes are advertised via OSPF. Which network statement would configure the OSPF process for networks 192.168.4.0, 192.168.5.0, 192.168.6.0, and 192.168.7.0, now located in the backbone area, and inject them into the OSPF domain?\n", "correct_answer": ["r1(config-router)# network 192.168.4.0 0.0.3.255 area 0\n"], "answers": ["r1(config-router)# network 192.168.4.0 0.0.15.255 area 0\n", "r1(config-router)# network 192.168.4.0 0.0.3.255 area 0\n", "r1(config-router)# network 192.168.4.0 0.0.15.255 area 1\n", "r1(config-router)# network 192.168.0.0 0.0.3.255 area 0\n", "r1(config-router)# network 192.168.0.0 0.0.15.255 area 1\n", "r1(config-router)# network 192.168.4.0 0.0.3.255 area 1\n"]}, {"id": 194, "question": "8. An administrator is configuring an OSPF router and would like the router to automatically advertise a default route into the OSPF domain even if there is no default route in the RIB. Which configuration will accomplish this?\n", "correct_answer": ["default-information originate always\n"], "answers": ["default-information originate always\n", "network 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 area 0\n", "network 0.0.0.0 255.255.255.255 area 0\n", "redistribute static\n"]}, {"id": 195, "question": "9. Which two variables must match between two OSPF routers to form a neighbor adjacency? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["hello and dead intervals\n", "area IDs\n"], "answers": ["K-values\n", "process IDs\n", "hello and dead intervals\n", "area IDs\n", "router priorities\n"]}, {"id": 196, "question": "10. In the planning stages for an OSPF deployment, which step can be taken to reduce router overhead by limiting the size of the link state databases, and LSA Type 1 and Type 2 propagation?\n", "correct_answer": ["Divide the OSPF network into multiple areas.\n"], "answers": ["Use redundant links and alternate paths between routers.\n", "Increase hello and dead interval timers.\n", "Ensure that the interfaces of all routers are configured for area 0.\n", "Divide the OSPF network into multiple areas.\n"]}, {"id": 197, "question": "11. Question as presented: Match the OSPF LSA types to their descriptions. (Not all options are used.)\n", "correct_answer": ["LSA type 3\n", "LSA type 5\n", "LSA type 1\n", "None\n", "LSA type 2\n", "LSA type 4\n"], "answers": ["LSA type 3\n", "LSA type 5\n", "LSA type 1\n", "None\n", "LSA type 2\n", "LSA type 4\n"]}, {"id": 198, "question": "12. Which two statements describe OSPF route summarization? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["The area 51 range 172.0.0.0 255.0.0.0 command identifies area 51 as the area that contains the range of networks to be summarized.\n", "The metric of the summary route is equal to the lowest cost network within the summary address range.\n"], "answers": ["OSPF can perform automatic summarization on major classful network boundaries even if no summarization commands are entered from the CLI.\n", "Once OSPF route summarization is configured, the summary route will be advertised even if none of the networks in the address range are in the routing table.\n", "Automatic OSPF route summarization is performed by the ABR.\n", "The area 51 range 172.0.0.0 255.0.0.0 command identifies area 51 as the area that contains the range of networks to be summarized.\n", "The metric of the summary route is equal to the lowest cost network within the summary address range.\n"]}, {"id": 199, "question": "13. What feature can be configured to filter routes as they are crossing an OSPF ABR?\n", "correct_answer": ["prefix list\n"], "answers": ["distribute list\n", "prefix list\n", "summarization\n", "route map\n"]}, {"id": 200, "question": "14. Which LSA type is advertised by all OSPF routers?\n", "correct_answer": ["type 1\n"], "answers": ["type 1\n", "type 2\n", "type 3\n", "type 4\n"]}, {"id": 201, "question": "15. Refer to the exhibit. What can be concluded about network 192.168.1.0 in the R2 routing table?\n", "correct_answer": ["This network was learned through summary LSAs from an ABR.\n"], "answers": ["This network has been learned from an internal router within the same area.\n", "This network was learned through summary LSAs from an ABR.\n", "This network is directly connected to the interface GigabitEthernet0/0.\n", "This network should be used to forward traffic toward external networks.\n"]}, {"id": 202, "question": "16. What period of time must elapse before an LSA is purged from the local LSBD if not updated with a new LSA?\n", "correct_answer": ["3600 seconds\n"], "answers": ["900 seconds\n", "1800 seconds\n", "3600 seconds\n", "7200 seconds\n"]}, {"id": 203, "question": "17. What action does an ABR take when it receives a type 1 LSA?\n", "correct_answer": ["it creates a type 3 LSA referencing the network in the type 1 LSA and forwards it into other OSPF areas.\n"], "answers": ["it drops the type 1 LSA.\n", "it floods the type 1 LSA into other nonbackbone areas.\n", "it creates a type 3 LSA referencing the network in the type 1 LSA and forwards it into other OSPF areas.\n", "it recreates the type 1 LSA into Area 0.\n"]}, {"id": 204, "question": "18. Which LSA type is flooded by a designated router to other OSPF routers within the same area?\n", "correct_answer": ["type 2\n"], "answers": ["type 1\n", "type 2\n", "type 3\n", "type 4\n"]}, {"id": 205, "question": "19. What does an OSPF area contain?\n", "correct_answer": ["routers that have the same link-state information in their LSDBs\n"], "answers": ["routers whose SPF trees are identical\n", "routers that share the same process ID\n", "routers that have the same link-state information in their LSDBs\n", "routers that share the same router ID\n"]}, {"id": 206, "question": "20. The network administrator has been asked to summarize the routes for a new OSPF area. The networks to be summarized are 172.16.8.0, 172.16.10.0, and 172.16.12.0 with subnet masks of 255.255.255.0 for each network. Which command should the administrator use to forward the summary route for area 15 into area 0?\n", "correct_answer": ["area 15 range 172.16.8.0 255.255.248.0\n"], "answers": ["area 0 range 172.16.8.0 255.255.248.0\n", "area 0 range 172.16.8.0 255.255.255.248\n", "area 15 range 172.16.8.0 255.255.248.0\n", "area 15 range 172.16.8.0 255.255.255.248\n"]}, {"id": 207, "question": "21. Which statement is true about the difference between OSPFv2 and OSPFv3?\n", "correct_answer": ["OSPFv3 routers do not need to have matching subnets to form neighbor adjacencies.\n"], "answers": ["OSPFv3 routers do not need to elect a DR on multiaccess segments.\n", "OSPFv3 routers use a 128 bit router ID instead of a 32 bit ID.\n", "OSPFv3 routers use a different metric than OSPFv2 routers use.\n", "OSPFv3 routers do not need to have matching subnets to form neighbor adjacencies.\n"]}, {"id": 208, "question": "22. Which two OSPFv3 LSAs advertise address prefix information? (Choose two.)\n", "correct_answer": ["type 8\n", "type 9\n"], "answers": ["type 1\n", "type 2\n", "type 4\n", "type 8\n", "type 9\n"]}, {"id": 209, "question": "23. Which statement describes the OSPFv3 configuration process?\n", "correct_answer": ["IPv6 routing must be enabled before the OSPFv3 process can start.\n"], "answers": ["The network command is used to enable OSPFv3 on an interface.\n", "The OSPFv3 router ID is manually configured as a 64-bit value.\n", "An address family must be initialized before OSPFv3 is enabled on an interface.\n", "IPv6 routing must be enabled before the OSPFv3 process can start.\n"]}, {"id": 210, "question": "24. What IPv6 address does an OSPFv3 router use as the destination address when sending hello packets to discover neighbors?\n", "correct_answer": ["FF02::5\n"], "answers": ["FF02::5\n", "FE80::2\n", "FF02::6\n", "FE80::1\n"]}, {"id": 211, "question": "25. Which is a difference between OSPFv2 and OSPFv3?\n", "correct_answer": ["OSPFv3 does not have built in support for neighbor authentication.\n"], "answers": ["OSPFv3 uses a 128-bit router ID.\n", "OSPFv3 and OSPFv2 use different protocol ID numbers.\n", "OSPFv3 uses different packet types than OSPFv2.\n", "OSPFv3 does not have built in support for neighbor authentication.\n"]}, {"id": 212, "question": "26. How are OSPFv3 routes that are learned from type 1 LSAs identified in the IPv6 routing table?\n", "correct_answer": ["O\n"], "answers": ["O\n", "EX\n", "IA\n", "OI\n"]}, {"id": 213, "question": "27. A network administrator enters the command ipv6 router ospf 64 in global configuration mode. What is the result of this command?\n", "correct_answer": ["The OSPFv3 process will be assigned an ID of 64.\n"], "answers": ["The router will be assigned an autonomous system number of 64.\n", "The router will be assigned a router ID of 64.\n", "The OSPFv3 process will be assigned an ID of 64.\n", "The reference bandwidth will be set to 64 Mb/s.\n"]}, {"id": 214, "question": "28. What benefit is provided to OSPFv3 with the two new LSA types, type 8 and type 9?\n", "correct_answer": ["They eliminate SPF calculations when interface addresses are added or changed.\n"], "answers": ["They redistribute NSSA LSAs into an area.\n", "They eliminate SPF calculations when interface addresses are added or changed.\n", "They permit area routers to locate ASBRs in other areas.\n", "They advertise default routes learned from other protocols into the OSPFv3 domain.\n"]}, {"id": 215, "question": "29. Refer to the exhibit. What two addresses will OSPFv3 neighbors connected to the g0/1 interface of R2 use as the destination address for sending OSPFv3 link-state updates to R2?\n", "correct_answer": ["FE80::2\n", "FF02::6\n"], "answers": ["FF02::5\n", "FE80::2\n", "2001:DB8:11::100\n", "2001:DB8:11:20::1\n", "FF02::6\n"]}, {"id": 216, "question": "30. Which type of LSA only exists on networks containing a DR?\n", "correct_answer": ["network\n"], "answers": ["router\n", "network\n", "AS external\n", "summary\n"]}, {"id": 217, "question": "31. Which type of LSAs are reduced through interarea summarization?\n", "correct_answer": ["type 3 LSAs from ABRs\n"], "answers": ["type 1 LSAs from all OSPF routers\n", "type 4 LSAs from ASBRs\n", "type 3 LSAs from ABRs\n", "type 2 LSAs from DRs\n"]}, {"id": 218, "question": "32. At what level does OSPF maintain a unique LSDB?\n", "correct_answer": ["area\n"], "answers": ["area\n", "network\n", "link\n", "router\n"]}, {"id": 219, "question": "33. Refer to the exhibit. Which address will R1 use as the source address for all OSPFv3 messages that will be sent to neighbors?\n", "correct_answer": ["FE80::1\n"], "answers": ["FF02::1\n", "2001:DB8:ACAD:A::1\n", "FE80::1\n", "FF02::5\n"]}, {"id": 220, "question": "34. Which OSPFv3 LSA type is used by ASBRs to announce routes learned through redistribution from other routing protocols?\n", "correct_answer": ["type 5\n"], "answers": ["type 3\n", "type 4\n", "type 5\n", "type 7\n"]}]